Hi there!
I'm your learning consultant, here to help you choose
the right training modality for your next project.Whether
you're building a quick reference guide, a full eLearning
course, or a hands-on workshop, the right format depends
on a few key factors.
Let's explore them together.
First, consider your audience size.
If your training is meant for a small group — say,
under 25 people — live or instructor-led sessions
can be very effective.
You'll have more opportunity for discussion and coaching.
But when you're training hundreds or even thousands
of employees, scalable options like eLearning modules
or video tutorials make much more sense.
They ensure everyone gets the same message, wherever
they are.
Next, think about your budget and available resources.
If you're working with a tight timeline or limited
funds, a well-designed job aid or quick reference
guide might be your best option.
When you have a moderate budget, consider an eLearning
course — it offers interactivity and can be reused
many times.
And if you have the time and funding, you might combine
formats — for example, a polished video paired with
short learning activities for reinforcement.
The nature of your content also plays a big role.
If you're simply sharing information or raising awareness,
a short video or microlearning module can do the job.
If you need to teach a process or build a skill,
interactive eLearning or simulations help learners
practice safely.
And for performance support — something learners use
on the job — job aids or quick guides are ideal.
When you put all these factors together — audience
size, budget, and content type — you can identify
the modality that gives your learners the most value.
There's no one-size-fits-all answer, but aligning
these three elements helps you make smart, strategic
training choices every time.
So the next time you're planning a training project,
take a quick consultative approach.
Ask yourself: Who's learning?
What's the goal?
And what resources do I have?
The right answers will naturally point you toward
the best training modality.
Thanks for joining me for this micro-consulting session —
and here's to designing learning experiences that
truly make an impact!